Let's look at the solution to our BTB
and BHT quiz. This time the question
was, how many times do we access the BTB
for each of these instructions? We have
a perfect BHT and a perfect BTB. The BTB
has four entries. The BHT has 16
entries. This doesn't really matter in
this part of the quiz. What you need to
know is that when you have both the BHT
and the
BTB, the BTB is accessed only if the BHT
says that this is a taken branch. If
this is not a taken branch, then we can
just increment the PC because this
instruction is not a taken branch and
because the BHD has perfect prediction,
the BTB will never be accessed. Same
thing here. And now you can tell that
for all non-branch
instructions, we will just have zero BTB
accesses because they are never
predicted to be taken branches. This
branch here is executed 100 times and is
always taken. So here the BTB will be
accessed 100 times. This branch is more
interesting. In every iteration that
stays in the loop, iterations where R1
is zero, 1, 2, etc. until
99 this branch is not taken. The BHT is
perfectly predicting it. So we don't
access the BTB at all. Only on the last
iteration when we are having R1 be 99
and we wrap around here and try to
compare again and this time we see that
R1 is 100 and jump out. Is this branch
taken? Because again we have a perfect
BHT that means that the only time the
BTB is accessed for this instruction is
that one last time when we are jumping
out of the loop. So the BTB will be
accessed only once because there is only
one time that this branch is actually
taken.